大家好，又是为大家做的洛克人的视频
Alright, hey guys, another Mega Man video for you.
今天要介绍的并不是 PET
Today it's not for any of these shiny shiny PET.
这是我刚刚收到的 Progress PET (PET III)
This is for my newest one, just came in the mail, the Progress PET.
呃，看起来还不错，做工也挺有分量
Umm... Very nice. Look to it very very solid build.
这个 PET 比这些任何一个的廉价感和塑料感都要少得多
And it feels less cheap and plasticky than any other ones.
这台 PET 对应的是《洛克人 EXE Stream》或《洛克人 EXE 5》
This one is for the Mega Man Stream or Mega Man Battle Network 5.
我会对其进行回顾，以及尝试给你们展示网络对战
So I'll do a quick overview and I'll try to show you guys the fight.
好，先把这些东西拿开。。。
Alright just move these stuffs out of the way, all the school views..
这是对应《洛克人 EXE 3》、《洛克人 EXE 传送》
和《洛克人 EXE Season》的 Plug-in PET（原话口误）
Umm... This is the Original PET for Battle Network 1 and 2
需要装入 4 节 7 号电池
Requires 4 AAA Batteries.
它有一个接头，然而没什么卵用
And it has the plug, it doesn't really do any thing with this.
如果你想了解的话可以看看我另外传的视频
I have a link to that video it if you wanna watch that.
我还没对这个 Advanced PET 做评测
This, I didn't do an overview to the Advanced PET.
正好就是下一代，这个是《洛克人 EXE 4》（和《洛克人 EXE Axess》）所使用的
Comes right after that one, this was featured in Battle Network 4.
我有一个链接（*短信声*），虽然在视频里我有它，
I'll have a link(*ring*), though the video I have that,
但这并不是一个评测
It's not an overview.
我之后可能会进行评测的
Anything I'll do one of those later, maybe.
而这个是《流星洛克人 1》的 Transer
And this is a Wave Transer for Star Force 1.
我也有个这个的视频
I have a video of this too,
如果想去看的话，点击它（YouTube 专用）
if you want to go, click on it,
你就能看到
you can watch that,
然后我最近才做的
and my most recent one I just did recently
是这个《洛克人 EXE 6》（和《洛克人 EXE Beast》《洛克人 EXE Beast+》）
所使用的Link PET
was for the Link PET.
你也可以从屏幕上点击它
You can check this one out right here on the screen
我会有个链接。
I'll have a link.
好的，
All right,
然后这也是最近的，
and then this is the most recent one, oh yeah,
这个需要两节 7 号 电池
this one uses 2 AAA(Batteries)
并且这个需要其中一种带奇怪按钮的电池
and this one uses one of those weird button batteries
Wave Transer 也是的
and so does the Wave Transer.
那么现在撇开一切事情，
All right now that intros out of the way,
这是有史以来最稳定的 PET
this is the only backwards compatible PET ever,
与其他 PET 使用同样的接口
uses the same a link cable as the other PET
就是你现在看到的一个普通耳机接口
is a standard headphone cable so you have.
举个例子……
Have an example... weird
如果你有一副耳机，2.5mm 标准的，
if you have got headphone, two headphone cable,
你可以从这里插入
you can plug it in plug in here,
应该不会有什么异状
probably won't actually do anything different,
是的，根本没有从耳机里播放音乐
yeah it doesn't play music through the headphones
同类型的也没用
but the same type of cord.
嗯……你实际上可以用
Umm... and you can actually use Battle Chips
第一代的对战晶片
from the first generation
我的意思是适用于 Advance PET的
I mean for the Advanced PET,
甚至美国版的，你可以看到也用英语
even the American ones as you can see it says "Battle Chip"
叫“Battle Chip”
in English.
然后这个是很有特色的PET
And this PET which is very nice feature,
并且这是 PET 有史以来最鲜明的特色，黑暗晶片。
and this is the first PET to ever feature, dark chips,
所以（呵呵）很有趣
so (whooo) that's fun.
目前我不打算用它
I'm not gonna be using this yet
因为我不知道它们能干什么
cause I don't know what they do.
所以我们要做的第一件事
So first thing we're gonna do
便是先来看看主屏幕
is look at the main screen,
我们看到按钮，我们现在是退出状态
here we got buttons we got canceled
好了，不知怎回事LED灯亮了
Okay, and led the lights up for some reason,
这是导航键，我的有些干硬了
a d-pad mine's a little bit stiff
然后这是对战晶片（插槽）打开按钮
and then the battle chip open button,
我的意思是，打开它
I mean that open it
然后这个插槽就打开了
and this opens up this slot.
如果你看了我的上一个视频的话，
I kind of wish they had the same thing
我有点希望他们在这些东西上也有这种东西
with if you watched my last video,
晶片在Link PET甚至Advanced PET
the chips go in a lot more in the (um...)
陷进去更多
Link PET and even the Advanced PET.
我喜欢伸出来很多的晶片
I like chips uh stick out too much.
并且这些伸出来有点多的正合我的口味
And these stick out a little bit too much for my tastes.
马上就好……
Just real quick... yeah,
我想无论如何都得把晶片插进Advanced PET更深一点
I feel like we go into the advanced PET more，regardless,
好的，抛开那个，我们看看Progress PET
all right, worried about that let's take a look,
我们来进行一次对战
let's go into a fight.
按按钮，拥有三种游戏模式
Press the button, it has three game main game modes
这是最重要的一个选项
this is most do the morph normal one
可以通向网络世界
which is Jack into the Internet.
好了，现在三个游戏模式出现了
I mean okay the three game mode should come up,
这里有角色扮演，对战
here we have RPG, Versus,
不过我只想要锦标赛
and I think we just want tournament.
我们进入角色扮演模式
Let's go to RPG,
我把咱们带到网络世界
I'll take us into the Internet
我们在这个家伙的地方，那是火野健一
we're in this guy's area that's Mr. Match.
这里是我们现在所处的位置
and here's the area we're in.
你必须找到规定物品，实际上是以便准备
You have to find these things in all ready to
登出网络世界
actually Jack out,
我知道这太坑了
it's pretty silly I know,
但这就是游戏设计的初衷
but that's the way the game is designed.
很酷的是，你其实可以在网络世界
You can actually walk around in the net
到处行走
which is pretty cool,
不过只有四个方向，人物移动就像这样子（死板）
there's only four direction so even look like
在此期间就按最接近的按钮
you can push in between just push the
去做你想要做的事
closest button to do what you want to do.
我们来找个地方
Let's go find a place.
电铃的铃声在响
The wave in the bell is working,
这游戏真的挺有趣的
this game is actually pretty interesting,
实际上在这底下使用LED指示灯
they actually use an LED under here
以便显示敌人在哪里，似乎
to show where the attackee is as opposed to
前代也有过
like a little been.
如果你玩过其他PET
Have you played any other PET
你知道我指那些奇怪的
you know what I mean by the weird
紧钉，我比较更喜欢这个
tacking I like this one kind of better.
好的，我们来开始一次对战
Alright, let's start a fight.
另外一个有趣的东西是他们
Another interesting thing is how they manage
如何管理你可以用多少晶片，
how many chips you could do,
并且最后会让你使用晶片能量
and the last one you use chip capacity,
所以每一个晶片意义都不大
so each of the chips are a low value.
好了我该移动了
Oh I gotta move,
好的，我们到这里
let's go here, all right.
现在它让我使用晶片能量
Right here it ask me use chip capacity,
我的意思是，看这，他要我使用晶片能量
I mean, look at it, it ask me to use my chip capacity
我在这张晶片上也可以看到
that I can see on this chip.
我们聚焦在这里看看
Let's let it focus a bit.
这张晶片是能力 10 的
This one has a chip capacity of 10,
所以我可以用它，并且你在玩这个游戏时
so I have a and when you played in this game,
你打得越多，你升级的越高
the more you fought, and the more you level up,
可以使用的晶片能量也就越高
the more hired chip capacity was.
我们晶片能量用完了
We ran out of chip capacity,
你现在只有洛克破坏炮
you only had your Mega Buster left.
这个游戏给你许多晶片使用
This game refers a number of chips you can use.
然后你可以看见这里写着我有三张晶片
As you can see here it says my chip list is three,
所以我的意思是他们准备用三张晶片
so I mean they gonna use three battle chips,
不过可以用任何三张
but can use any three battle chips,
所以我只需开始对战就行了
so I can just start off the battle,
忘掉你的晶片，虽然这样做不太靠谱
forget your chip, not really great for balance,
不过我想很有趣
but pretty interesting, I guess.
如果能量用完了
You have to worry about mega chips
就得担心Mega晶片。好了，
using up all your capacity. All right,
现在该是使用洛克破坏炮的时间了
and right now it's using Mega Buster
不过我还没插入任何晶片
because I didn't slide any chips,
那么，插入晶片，按下取消键
well slot in the chip and press cancel,
切换之后获得晶片
and after switch to get chip,
这里显示有300攻击力，标准晶片
it says there's 300 attack and it's a standard,
所以我们按OK以确认
so let's press ok to confirm,
我不知道这什么鬼意思
I don't know what that means...
好的，我猜要移除晶片
Okay, it says remove Battle Chip, I guess,
然后我们正在打一个空气曲棍球伢子
and we're fighting us an air-hockey guy.
这就是他的移动轨迹的样子
That's what his moves look goes like
你看到他斜着过来，很酷
you saw it going up diagonally, pretty cool.
然后打中了我
And it actually hit me,
并且你可以看到每一个嵌盘都能命中
and you can see each of the panels are hits.
我实在喜欢他们做的这些
I really like how they do that,
然后我该出场了，射击
and now this is my move, shoots out,
来看看嵌盘如何命中的
come on see how panels it hits,
在整个背景下，全部被毁坏了
in the entire background and completely demolished.
别担心，我会再打一次的
Don't worry, I'm gonna do another fight
为了让这个更加明显
to this a little bit more fair.
我只想展示一下它实际上移动的轨迹
I just want to show off how it shows the actual movements.
所以基本上，如果你有一张Giga晶片
So basically if you have a Giga chip
或者高等级的Mega晶片
or a high-level mega chip,
你就可以在很大的范围内攻击
you can just blaze through pretty much any area,
拥有这个你甚至可能解决掉
with this you could probably even take out most of
第一批大型敌人
a couple the first couple bosses.
好的，我现在只能录五分钟了
All right, I'm only  five minutes into the video,
不过我觉得还可以再进行一次对战
but I think I was time for one more battle,
所以至少也得给你们看看晶片更多的明细
so gonna at least show you the finer details of the chips,
然后为了离开这里
and in order to exit the area,
我相信你得达到一定等级
I believe you have to be a certain level
那就意味着你必须打足够的人
so that means you have to fight enough people
也或许是依据对战质量决定的，我还不清楚
or maybe it's by fights, I'm not sure yet.
这些角落有点怪怪的
The corners are kind of confusing
毕竟你只能从四个方向移动
because you can only walk in four directions.
好的，又是一个炸弹男，这名字是用来给病毒起的
Alright, we got a bomb boy, a virus okay they're called.
只需使用几张对战晶片，我相信他会被打败的
Just use a bubble of battle chip I think he's fired
目前状况还好，按左键，右键
typos fine now, you press left and right,
好，他是五级的，我觉得……
okay he's level five, I believe...
我不知道这到底什么鬼意思
I don't know what hell that means,
好的，我觉得这应该是决定谁先上
all right, this decides who goes first, I think.
那么我现在觉得他先上了
So I think that means he goes first,
我们先离开他这里
let's move out of his way out,
想着这里的炸弹
thinking for the bomb here.
好吧，这通常是用洛克破坏炮
Okay this usually Mega Buster,
首先我们可以看看到底有什么用
first we can see how that works,
这不会消耗我的晶片能量
it doesn't take away from my chip capacity,
洛克破坏炮……我似乎先上了
Mega Buster... oh I go first apparently
现在只需要等待其慢速的加载了
now it's just roll over for slow processing power,
然后你就能看到洛克破坏炮射击了一整列
and you saw that Mega Buster shot all across that row,
现在他在中间一列，然后我才他在用炸弹炸我
now he's in the middle row and he's shooting his bomb, I guess.
有些步数可能需要好几秒钟
Some of the moves would take multiple seconds,
呃……看起来有点奇怪
eh... look a little bit weird,
不过你可以看见它会那样在平面上移动
but you could see it would kind of push across the field,
然后那就是我想去类比的
so that's what I was trying to resemble.
好的，我们有能力 3 的晶片
All right, we got chip capacity of three,
插入水枪，攻击力 30，标准晶片
a slide in a bubbler, attack thirty, standard,
怪怪的，嘿，那是唯一的（不知道什么）面板
weird, hey that's the only hits one panel, huh
看起来有点奇怪，确认，坚定些，水枪
it's kind of weird. Confirm, take your stout, bubbler,
哇，他真的使用了飞溅攻击了，我觉得真是太棒了
wow it actually does Splash Damage I think that's pretty cool.
然后他现在移动来攻击我
and now he's hitting me with his move,
哎呀，他直接就把我干掉许多
oh yeah direct hit so much damage, he did.
不算太差，好吧
it didn't do too bad. All right,
我们就认为他这次还在同一列，有点怪……
let's I think he's in the same row this time, it's kind of weird
然后你就看不到他
you can't see afterwards.
现在我的能力下降到 2 点了
Now I see my capacity went down to two,
那么是该用用黑暗晶片（毒品）了
so now what it's used a Dark Chip,
让我们来看看会发生什么
let's see what it does.
做好最坏的打算……
What's the worst that could happen,
我传输数据了，（不小心按错了）
I pass the megabytes, ooh by accident,
SP，黑暗隐形，HP
from SP, Dark Invisible, HP,
这似乎并没有告诉我的 HP 有多少
it doesn't mean my HP apparently,
我觉得这样下去所有都会挂的
I think every would actually die,
不过特别的事情也可能发生
something special would happen.
嘿，我的 HP 恢复了
Hey recovery through my HP,
好的，既然他看不见我，似乎他消失了
okay, so since he couldn't see me he missed apparently,
我们现在还有一张晶片，有很多 HP
okay I have one chip left and I have plenty of HP,
好吧，那么黑暗晶片刚才没起什么作用
alright, so that Dark Chip didn't do anything just yet,
我猜我们要挂了
I guess we'd have to die off,
对于黑暗晶片我会再上传一个视频
try to upload another video with that,
呃……我们最后用个时间炸弹吧
uh let's use time bomb for our last one,
为了……你懂的
just for... just cuz you know.
移除晶片
Moved out of chip,
好的，就像这样，搞了些爆炸
okay as he saw it like, did a little explosion thing,
现在他被干掉了，我们赢了
and now he's dead, we win.
我认为我们可以按左键和右键
I think we could we could press left and right
然后看你的信息
then and see your stats.
好吧，你从这里也可以看你的信息
All right, you can see your stats from here too
如果按这个确定的按钮
if you press this button which is confirmed,
你可以看你的状态，对战信息
you can look at your status, versus stats,
我不能再按了，这里显示我们的 HP 是 109，攻击……等下
I can't press it again there we are HP 109, attack... wait,
109... 我不太清楚我之前的 HP 是多少了
109... I think that I don't remember correctly when my HP was before,
不过我会记下我最大的 HP 值
but am I taking away one for my max HP
没有低于 5
but it doesn't down over five,
该多加注意了
was sure to pay attention more.
我把它归结为基础时
As am i attribute with standard,
我觉得你可以双倍，但在这个游戏里我不清楚
I think you can double, so in this game I'm not sure,
我们来看看我们能不能退出
let's see if we can actually exit,
并且这个视频已经 10 分钟了……
while this video is almost 10 minutes already...
好的，我们还不知道我是不是去了下个地方
Okay we haven't figured I had gone to the next area,
你不需要去想我们要不要去打一群人
you ever think we don't have to fight a number of people
因为这东西在给我们显示信息
because you're showing us our stats,
那么好吧，该登出了
so okay but yeah the jack out,
你得去我们之前来到的那个地方
you have to go back to one of those scenes we showed before,
很酷的是，你可以按取消键
you can actually cancel virus battle
退出与病毒的对战
by pressing cancel which is cool,
然后那里有个登出点，走近它，点击确认
and there's a Jack out point, walk up to it, and press confirm,
就可以（登出了）
get Jack to...
哇。我希望你们可以喜欢这个视频
Wow. Alright I hope you guys enjoyed this video,
有些抱歉，这比我其他的视频有些长
I'm sorry there's a little bit longer than some my other ones,
但是……好吧，那么如果你喜欢这个视频的话
but um... yeah, so if you like this video,
去下面，点击"喜欢"
go ahead and like it,
并且如果你想看看我以后想做什么的话
and if you want to see me do something later in the future,
我会尽量在评论中做回复
I'll try to just post in the comments,
在我搞懂这些菜单到底什么意思之前
don't try to do as soon as I can find out
别去做这件事
what these menus mean,
下次见了，拜拜
and I'll see you all later, Bye.